「嗨，貨鼓郎」
# Hey, Mister Tambourine Man #
「為我演奏一曲」
# Play a song for me #
- 「在這鏗鏘的早晨」 - B
- # In the jingle-jangle morning... # - "B."
- 「讓我與你同去」 - A
- # I'll come following... # - "A."
玩得開心嗎？親愛的
Man: You having fun, sweetheart?
是的
Girl: Yes.
啊
Ahh.
寶貝，我希望你做得比我好
Well, I hope you're doing better than me, baby.
- 你做的是什麼？ - 為媽媽做的項鏈
- What are you making? - A necklace for Mom.
是嗎？讓我看看
Yeah? Let me see.
哇，又一條？
Wow. Another one?
- 是呀 - 親愛的？
- Yes. - Woman: Honey?
今天有兩條了？
That's two today.
- 是呀 - 哦
- Yeah. - Yeah.
親愛的？
Honey?
- 在 - 幫我開一下門吧？
- Yeah? - Waiting for the help to get that?
我覺得你和我都是幫手
I thought you and I were the help.
- 洗手吃飯去，小南瓜 - 好
- Go wash up for dinner, pumpkin. - Okay.
嗯，聞起來很香 可以外賣嗎？
Mmm, smells nice. That takeout?
媽媽，看…
Mommy, look at-
不！
No!
不！啊！
No! Ahh!
哦！別，別，別
Oh! No no no!
你沒法跟天斗
You can't fight fate.
我們得離開這鬼地方了 快走吧！
Man: We gotta get the fuck out of here. Come on!
哦，不，不
Oh! Oh no!
不！
Thug: No!
- 你他媽在幹什麼？ - 不！
- What the fuck are you doing? - No!
媽的停下！ 我們快走！
Fucking stop! Let's go!
他媽給我閉嘴！
Just shut the fuck up!
不！
No!
棒極了
It's cool.
小孩喜歡我
Kids like me.
不，希瑟
No! Heather!
不，不！
No no!
《守法公民》
- 尼克 - 佈雷，怎麼了？
- Nick. - Bray, what's happenin'?
威利斯是我一起划艇的朋友 他小孩的案子怎麼樣了？
Willis is a rowing buddy of mine. Where are we on his kid's case?
- 威利斯？ - 是啊
- Willis? - Yeah.
- 哦，我把他踢到少管所去了 - 為什麼那樣做？
- Oh, I kicked it down to juvie. - Why did you do that?
因為這案子很沒勁 當他承認謀殺時
'Cause the case was a dog. The kid was only 15 years old
這個孩子才只有15歲
when he committed the murder.
你捨得影響你那百分之九十五的定罪率記錄麼
You wouldn't want to jeopardize your 95% conviction rate.
- 其實是百分之九十六 - 現在九十六了？
- It's actually 96%. - 96% now?
是的，你得好好記記賬本了
Yes. You gotta keep your books better than that.
你知道，如果我沒理解錯的話 我會說你想取代我的職位
You know, if I didn't know any better, I'd say you were gunning for my job.
你確實說的對
You do know better.
而你也該知道我的目標要更高
And you know that I'm aiming much higher than that.
他們請求撤回此案
Woman: They filed a motion to dismiss,
但艾布拉姆法官堅持不同意
but there's no way that Judge Abrams honors it.
我想我們可以搬出RICO法令 （反犯罪組織侵蝕合法組織法）
I think that we can get him on RICO.
莎拉,這陣子你就只做了這些?
All that time and that's what you come back with, Sarah?
你也許應該重新評估下自己的能力
You might want to reevaluate your research skills.
- 還有其它信息麼? - 她說得對
- What else have we got? - Nick: She's right.
什麼意思？
Mr. Rice?
RICO是設計處理這類事情的
RICO's designed for this kind of thing.
查一下《有組織犯罪控制法》901章
Check out section 901 of the Organized Crime Control Act.
你就會讓莎拉處理這個案子
And you should let Sarah try this case too.
瑞斯先生，我記得以前 這屋子是我說的算
Mr. Rice, last I checked, I was running this room.
她已經做了案件調查的工作 我會監督這個
She's already done the leg-work. I'll oversee it.
我的意思是海倫·凱勒可以試試這個案子 （海倫·凱勒：上世紀美國傑出女性）
I mean, Helen Keller could try this case.
好吧，青年才俊 她搞砸了，就算在你頭上
Okay, Boy Wonder, she fucks up, it's on you.
坎特雷爾想見你
Cantrell wants to see you.
好的，我馬上就去
All right, I'll be right there.
不，尼克 他想見尼克
No, Nick. He wants to see Nick.
你仍在折磨布林漢姆？
You still torturing Bringham?
這麼說吧，我不像他那麼看重哈佛學位
Nick: Let's just say I'm less impressed with his Harvard degree than he is.
呵，我們不能都去上福德漢姆
Well, we can't all have gone to Fordham.
我上過福德漢姆夜校
I went to Fordham night school.
知道我在福德漢姆夜校學到什麼了嗎？
You know what I learned in Fordham night school?
法學院裡學不到什麼法律
Law school's got nothing to do with law.
我猜你逃了職場哲學的課
Guess you skipped the course on inter-office politics.
我所需要的就是陪審團喜歡我 這不是你教我的嗎，喬納斯？
All I need is a jury to like me. Isn't that what you told me, Jonas?
謝爾頓案件… 進展到哪了？
The Shelton case- where are we?
昨晚出了點差錯，伯奇法官那邊
It went sideways last night- Judge Burch.
啊…
Ahh.
壞消息，現在怎樣辦？
Bad news. What now?
- 作筆交易吧 - 尼克，他們殺了小女孩
- Let's make the deal. - They killed a little girl, Nick.
- 這是一個不完美的體制 - 而我們是不完美公僕
- It's an imperfect system. - And we its imperfect servants.
- 不過，你還是可以贏下這個案子 - 不，不能去冒險
- However you could win this case. - No, can't take that chance.
有一些公正總比沒有公正好
Some justice is better than no justice at all.
那你得去告訴那位丈夫
You need to tell the husband.
好的 那是我的工作
Okay. That's part of my job.
很好，因為他正在等著你，現在！
Good, because he's waiting for you right now.
什麼？
What?
- 你怎麼樣？ - 還好，你怎麼樣？
- How are you doing? - Good. How are you doing?
還好 坐吧，坐吧
Good. Sit. Sit.
呃，一直沒有你的消息
Well, I didn't hear back from you
所以我寫了一些東西關於這案子
and made some notes on the case.
我有些好主意
I had some good ideas.
好，讓我來看看
Yeah, let me take a look at it.
恩，它們只是…
Well, they're just-
我正打算跟你談這個
I was gonna talk to you about those.
你信任我麼？
Do you trust me?
你信任我麼，克萊德？
Do you trust me, Clyde?
是的，當然
Yeah, of course.
多比同意作證檢舉阿米
Darby has agreed to testify against Ames.
有了多比的證詞
With Darby's testimony,
阿米就會被判死刑
Ames will go to death row.
嗯，那…多比會怎樣？
Um, what about- what about Darby then?
多比將被定罪謀殺
Darby will plead guilty to murder.
- 幾級？ - 三級
- In what degree? - Third.
他會服刑多久？五年？
He serves, what? Five years...
最多？
at best?
很抱歉，我不明白
I don't understand. I'm sorry.
我們遇到了麻煩 法官裁定DNA證據不被採用
We had a setback. The judge ruled that the DNA was inadmissible.
- 什麼？ - 非法證據排除原則
- What? - Exclusionary rule.
辯方律師的伎倆
The opposing counsel maneuvered it.
你說過這個部分容易辨認
You said this part of the case was clear-cut.
我們在他的襯衫上發現了血跡
We had the blood on his shirt-
這也涵蓋在同樣的原則下
It's covered under the same rule.
那法醫的其它證據呢？
What about the rest of the forensic evidence?
那些都不是決定性的，克萊德
It's not conclusive, Clyde.
好吧，沒關係 我看見…我看見他們的臉了
Okay, that's okay. 'Cause I saw- I saw their faces.
我親眼看到他們行兇 他們殺了我的小女兒，尼克
I saw them do it. I mean, he killed my little girl, Nick.
克萊德，你暈過去了 你的證詞無法令人信服
You blacked out, Clyde. Your testimony won't be reliable.
你站上證人席時 辯方律師會把你撕碎的
You get on the stand and the defense will tear you apart.
不，不，陪審團會相信我的
No no, the jury's gonna believe me though.
- 因為這就是真相，我們可以… - 我們會輸的
- Because it's the truth! We can- - We can lose.
然後我們會一無所獲
And then we'd have nothing.
你會浪費一整年的時間 花費百萬美元
You will waste a whole year, spend millions of dollars,
然後他倆雙雙逍遙法外
and then both of them could end up going free.
尼克，他們都有罪 尤其是多比！
Nick, both of them are guilty, especially Darby!
- 你知道這些 - 這與你知道什麼無關，克萊德
- You know that. - It's not what you know, Clyde.
而是你能在法庭上證明什麼
It's what you can prove in court.
請別與這人做這個交易
Please don't make a deal with this man.
請別與這人交易，他是禽獸
Please don't make a deal with this man. He's a monster-
對不起，協議已經達成了，對不起
I'm sorry, the deal is done. I'm sorry.
我達成了協議
I made the deal.
什麼？你怎麼可以那樣做？
What? How could you do that?
這就是司法體系運作的方式
This is just how the justice system works.
聽著，我知道你現在不認可這點
Listen, I know you don't think it right now,
但這其實是我們的勝利
but this is a victory for us.
你們辦公室已經認可這個協議了嗎？
Woman: Your office has certified this agreement?
是的，法官閣下
Yes, Your Honor.
雷諾斯先生，今天有無高見與法庭分享？
Mr. Reynolds, any great insights to share with the court today?
我是辯方律師，法官閣下 我沒多少高見
I'm a defense attorney, Your Honor. I don't have many of those.
沒有，法官大人，沒有意見了
No, Your Honor. No insights.
很好，那我相信我們可以毫無阻礙地
Good, then I trust that we can move forward with Mr. Ames's trial
推進阿米先生的判決了 審批日期將近了
unimpeded by continuances. A triaI date is imminent.
喂？
Yeah?
瑞斯先生，我的法庭不允許講手機
There's no cell phones in my courtroom, Mr. Rice.
- 我們說過了… - 抱歉
- We've been over this- - I'm sorry.
一遍地，又一遍地
- and over this, over this...
是的，我有些急事…
Yeah, I had some exigent business I-
下次我就要沒收了
Next time it's mine.
- 啊，你結婚了嗎？ - 你說什麼？
- Ah, you married? - Excuse me?
你結婚了？
Are you married?
請繼續噴 這樣我就能毀了你
Please fuck this up so I can destroy you.
我不想害人
I wish ill for no man,
不過阿米罪有應得
but Ames deserves to suffer for what he did.
我是說，你沒法跟天斗的對吧？
I mean, you can't fight fate, right?
尼克
Nick.
一旦你做了決定 就要學會接受…繼續往前
Cantrell: Once you make a decision, live with it- move on.
這份工作，最大的資產就是短暫記憶
This job, your best asset's a short memory.
別自責了，其他很多人都這樣干了
Don't beat yourself up. Too many other people out there doing that already.
看，現在那邊就有一些人
Look, there's some of them right now.
是不是到了時間你要給我講些寓言
Isn't this where you tell me some type of old fable
或者啟蒙故事的了
or wives' tale-
好了，好了，我想到一個了
All right, all right, I got one.
當馬可·奧勒留走過羅馬時代廣場時
Marcus Aurelius hired a servant to walk behind him
他雇了一個僕人跟在身後
as he made his way through the Roman town square.
這個僕人唯一的工作就是
And this servant's only job
當別人讚美他時，在他耳邊低聲說
was to whisper in his ear when people praised him,
你只是個凡人 你只是個凡人
"You're only a man. You're only a man. "
- 好了，凡人 - 好吧，凡人
- Okay, man? - Okay, man.
- 好吧，凡人 - 那是胡扯
- Okay, man. - That's some bullshit.
講得很好
That's good.
我認為你不理解這個故事的含義
Nick: I don't think you even know what that story means.
你沒懂，尼克 他們說什麼並不重要
You're missing the point, Nick. It doesn't matter what they say.
好吧，我懂了
Okay, I got this now.
好吧，女士們先生們 一個個來
All right, ladies and gentlemen, one at a time, one at a time.
那麼你們會要求死刑？
So you'll be seeking the death penalty?
- 對於魯柏特·阿米，我們會 - 那多比呢？
- For Rupert Ames, we will be. - And for Darby?
他已經承認謀殺 但他是個污點證人
He has pled guilty to murder, but he is a cooperating witness.
地方檢察院已經動用了一切資源
The DA's office has committed all of its resources
確保司法公正
to ensure that justice will be served.
你們有沒有做一些…
Woman: Did you make any kind of-
你覺得對多比而言是一個合理的宣判？
Man: Do you think this is a fair sentence for Darby?
我只想為你站在我的這邊說聲謝謝
I just wanted to say thanks for being in my corner.
司法體系運作時很不錯，對吧？
It's nice when the system works, right?
離我遠點
Get away from me.
走，走
Officer: Move. Move.
我們走吧
Let's go.
- 尼克？ - 嗨
- Nick? - Hey.
嗯，怎麼了？
Nuh-uh, what happened?
什麼怎麼了？
What happened to what?
怎麼了？
What's wrong?
你稱我的工作乏味，C-？
You call my job boring. "C-"?
是的
Yes.
嗯，好了，現在…
Well... okay now...
你得告訴我怎麼了？
you gonna tell me what's wrong?
我可以先跟我女兒聊一會嗎？
Can I talk to my daughter for a little bit?
- 哦，拜託，別，別 - 我要躺下了
- Oh, please. No no no. - Gonna lay down.
拜託了
Please?
首先，這是你父親在講話
First of all, this is your father speaking.
- 哦，她不會知道 - 你怎麼知道
- Yeah, she didn't know that. - You never know.
我想要你盡量呆在裡面
I want you to stay in there as long as you can.
因為外面有很多瘋子和混蛋
'cause there's a lot of crazy-ass people out here.
措辭…
Language.
你媽媽是個難纏的人物，但…
Your mother's a hardass, but-
我在場呢
I'm right here.
爸爸…爸爸想要你出來當爸爸的小女孩
And Daddy- Daddy wants you to come out and be Daddy's little girl.
我要她出來 因為她壓在我的膀胱上
Woman: I want her to come out 'cause she's on my bladder.
啊
Nick: Ahh!
誰看到我的手機了嗎？ （十年後）
Anybody seen my phone?
- 嘿，你看到我手機了嗎？ - 沒拴在你的手上嗎？
- Hey, have you seen my phone? - It's not strapped to your hand?
沒，沒拴在我手上
No, it's not strapped to my hand.
- 爸爸 - 嗯？
- Daddy? - Yeah?
不打算吃點我做的法式吐司嗎？
You're not gonna have some of my French toast?
- 法式吐司，你在做法式吐司？ - 嗯
- French toast? You made French toast? - Mm-hmm.
我不吃了，親愛的 我就要遲到了
I can't, honey. I'm running late.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，來一口…嗯
All right, here- Mmm.
- 嗯，味道很不錯 - 謝謝
- Mmm, that's good. - Thank you.
- 你自己做的？ - 嗯
- You did this by yourself? - Mm-hmm.
我要把這一盤都帶到單位去
I'm just gonna take this whole plate to work.
嗯…不行
All right- no.
你才十歲嗎？
You're only 10 years old?
- 比你媽做得還好吃 - 我聽到了
- You better than your mother. - I heard that.
很香呀
Smells good in here. Your lifeline.
早安，寶貝 親一個
'Morning, baby. Give me a kiss.
嗯!下午去你女兒的獨奏會嗎？
Mmm! You going to your daughter's recitaI this afternoon?
我還以為你會帶演奏會DVD回來看呢
Um, I thought you were gonna order the DVDs.
看視頻可不一樣，尼克
Video's not the same, Nick.
媽媽，沒關係 爸爸得工作，我理解
Mom, it's okay. Dad's got to work, I know.
瞧？沒關係，爸爸得工作 那麼老爸今天做什麼？
See? It's all right. Dad's got to work. And what is Dad doing today?
- 把壞蛋關起來 - 那他為何那樣做？
- Lock up bad guys. - And why does he do that?
- 來保護我們的安全 - 對了
- To keep us safe. - Yeah.
她理解 因為他想我們安安全全的
She understands. 'Cause he wants us to be safe.
- 寶貝，拿你的大提琴 - 好
- Baby, get your cello. - All right.
- 非常感謝 - 不客氣
- Thank you so much. - You're welcome.
- 小朱莉婭寶貝 - 唔
- Little Julia Child. - Mmm.
你知道她才十歲，對吧？
You know she's 10 years old, right?
- 你知道嗎？ - 當然
- You know that? - I know that.
她無法理解你為何不在身邊
She doesn't understand why you're never around.
好人，壞人… 你就只會對她講這些話
This good-guy, bad-guy stuff- that's just talk to her.
別這樣了，好吧
Don't do this, come on.
我今天不能去
I can't come today.
你知道你連她的一次獨奏會都沒去過
You know you have not been to one recitaI-
- 她演了多少次了？ - 行了
- How many has she had? - Enough.
好了 好吧，我們會要視頻回來
Okay. Well, we'll get the video,
我們坐下，然後一家人一起看
we'll sit down and we'll watch it together as a family.
我愛你
I love you.
好吧？
All right?
- 謝謝你的吐司 - 我愛你！
- Thank you for the toast. - Love you.
- 我也愛你！ - 拜
- Love you too! - Bye.
我愛你
Love you.
哼
Huh.
- 奇普怎樣了？ - 切斯特了
- So how's Chip? - It's Chester.
奇普哪去了？ 我喜歡奇普
What happened to Chip? I liked Chip.
沒奇普了
There is no Chip.
現在也不是切斯特 只是他不停打電話
And now there's no Chester. He kept calling.
- 莎拉，這是好事 - 我知道，但我一直拒絕
- Sarah, that's a good thing. - I know, but I kept cancelling.
我的案子太多了
My caseload's crazy.
你知道如果你不想跟這個案子 你可以不來
You know you don't have to go to this if you don't want to.
是的，我懂，我…
Yeah, I do. I...
是什麼感覺？
What's it like?
沒什麼 像看著某人睡著
No biggie. Like watching somebody fall asleep.
除了叫不醒這步驟
Except for the not-waking-up part.
還在困擾你嗎？
Does it bother you?
再也不會了
Not anymore.
莎拉，你穿高跟鞋真得好看
Sarah, your legs are looking real good in those heels.
滾開
Fuck off.
你來幹嘛，雷諾斯？ 你為何在這，你的DVD壞了嗎？
What are you doing here, Reynolds? Your DVD player broken?
阿米沒有親人，我覺得有人應該為他而來
Ames has no family. I felt like someone should be here for him.
哦，你真好
Wow, that's nice.
吸氣
Breathe.
魯柏特·阿米，你還有什麼要說的麼？
Rupert Ames, do you have anything you want to say?
是的
Yeah.
呃
Uh-huh.
我做的是錯事
Ames: What I did that night was wrong.
我不該去那的
I should have never been there.
但我向天發誓 我沒有殺害那些人
But I swear to God, I didn't kill those people.
今天這裡死的人搞錯了
The wrong man's dying here today.
The wrong man's dying.
就這些
That's all.
看著我
Look at me.
看著我！
Look at me!
啊！靠！
Ahh! Fuck!
靠！
Fuck!
啊！靠！
Ahh! Fuck!
哦，天那
Oh, God.
- 哦，天呀 - 帶她…帶她出去
- Oh, God. - Take her- take her out.
- 到底怎麼回事 - 我不知道
- What the hell is going on? - I don't know.
啊！
Ahhh!
是什麼引起犯人這種意外的反應？
Man: What could have caused the unexpected reaction of the inmate?
我們會給你消息的
We'll keep you informed.
你沒事吧？啊?
You okay? Huh?
嗯
Yeah.
有人殺了那個你本想殺的人？
So somebody killed the guy you were trying to kill?
這個叫什麼來著？
What are we calling this?
明顯違反第8修正案賦予他的權利
Clear violation of his Eighth Amendment rights-
- 殘忍與非正當刑罰 - 法學院…
- cruel and unusual punishment. - Law schooI.
嗯，那機器…平時是如何運作的？
Yeah. The machine- how does it work on a good day?
它是按無痛設計的
It's designed to be pain-free.
按特定的程序注射三劑藥物
It's three drugs administered in a specific order.
基於這點，我們應該假設…
From this point on, we're operating under the assumption
機器被動了手腳
that the machine was corrupted.
我們需要所有能接近那機器的人員名單
We're gonna need a list of all the people with access to that machine.
- 我的人不會幹這種事的 - 我能理解，典獄長
- My people would not do this. - I appreciate that, Warden,
但我不只要通行證和請假條之類的
but I'm gonna need more than a hall pass and a note from Mom.
探長，機器後面發現了這個
Detectives, got this off the back of the machine.
- 你看看 - 我看看
- Check it out. - Let me see it.
在那
Man: Right there.
「沒法跟天斗」
"Can't fight fate. "
尼克，怎麼了？
Cantrell: What is it, Nick?
在入室侵犯時，阿米的同夥
During the home invasion, Ames's accomplice
曾對其中一名受害者說 「你沒法跟天斗」這話
said to one of the vics, "You can't fight fate. "
他在法庭上也和我說過同樣的話
And then he said the same thing to me in the courtroom- prick.
但我記不得他的名字了
I can't remember his name, though.
看一下這個…是你們要找的人嗎？
Detective: Have a look at this- your guy?
- 克拉倫斯·詹姆士·多比 - 他是個人渣
- Nick: Clarence James Darby. - Detective: He's a cutie.
- 你跟他有關係？ - 放了他一馬
- You got history with him? - Nick: Put him away.
恩，才三年 現在殺人才關這麼短嗎？
All right, three years. That the going rate for murder these days?
有減刑的情況
There was extenuating circumstances.
唯一減刑的情況是他沒幹這事
The only extenuating circumstances should be he didn't do it.
還是在馬裡恩監獄待了三年 該死的角鬥士學院
Still, three years at Marion? Fucking gladiator academy.
你指望他變成模範市民？
You expect him to come back a modeI citizen?
好了，如果你們這幫學者 沒污染犯罪現場的話
Well, if you scholars wouldn't contaminate the crime scenes,
我能把他們關久一點
I could keep them locked up longer.
當局拒絕對此發表評論
TV reporter: Authorities have refused to comment at this point,
但不排除有違規的行為
but foul play cannot be ruled out.
該罪犯已經在死囚區待了10年…
The prisoner had been on death row for the past 10 years-
他的名字是魯珀特·阿米
his name, Rupert Ames.
我們所知道的一點是
Female reporter: All we know at this point
本應該是無痛行刑
is what was supposed to be a painless execution
變成了恐怖片中的情景
has turned into something out of a horror film.
喂？
Yeah?
- 克拉倫斯·多比？ - 誰？
- Disguised voice: Clarence Darby? - Who's this?
三樣關於你的:桌上的可卡因
That's strike three for you: coke on the table,
地板上的婊子…監獄裡的生活
bitch on the floor- life in prison.
你他媽是誰？
Who the fuck is this?
看看窗外…南邊
Voice: Look out your window, south side.
- 開玩笑嗎？起來！ - 啊！
- Is this a joke? Get up! - Ahh!
南邊
South side.
他媽的
Motherfucker.
靠，別擋路！
Shit. Out of the way!
- 蹲下！ - 你們都瘋了！
- Stay down! - You're all crazy!
他往北去了 快上，上
He's heading north! Go go!
- 該死 - 快去，快去，走
- Damn. - Move it, move it. Go on!
- 現在怎麼做？ - 擦掉槍上的指紋
- What now? - Wipe the prints off the gun.
- 然後把槍丟掉 - 不，不
- Get rid of it. - No no.
你開了六槍了，天才 你帶了彈藥了麼？
You fired six times, genius. You bring any ammunition?
- 扔了吧 - 你為什麼這樣做？
- Lose it. - Why are you doing this?
我不想讓你進監獄
I want to keep you out of prison.
看到那廢棄的工廠了嗎？ 去那
See the abandoned factories? Go toward them.
為什麼？
Why?
那裡有輛警車，車內有個警察
There's a cop car there with a cop in it.
該死的怎麼回事？
What the fuck?
我電暈了他，但他在90秒內就會醒來
I Tasered him, but he'll be waking up in about 90 seconds,
所以你最好快點
so you'd better move.
起來了，你這個賤人 快他媽起來！
Rise and fucking shine, bitch. Wake the fuck up!
我們走！ 快他媽開車！
Let's go! Start the fucking car!
- 好的！ - 快點
- Okay! - Do it.
- 別衝動，別衝動… - 快點！
- Take it easy, take it- - Come on!
- 好，我們走 - 別衝動
- Okay, let's go. - Take it easy.
我們走，掛檔呀 笨蛋，現在！
Let's go! Get in gear, shithead, now!
現在！走，走，快走！
Do it! Go go go!
他媽滾出去！
Get the fuck out.
快走吧！
Let's go.
給我趴到那邊去
Get the fuck down there!
那麼，我妻子怎麼辦？ 我的小女兒？
Okay. What about my wife? My little girl?
- 我再也見不到她們了 - 慘極了，是吧？
- I'll never see them again. - Fucked up, ain't it?
哦，哦，哦
Oh oh oh.
不介意我接個電話吧？
You don't mind if I take this, do you?
我的守護天使
My guardian angel.
我深為感激
I am impressed.
你知道我為什麼再也見不到我妻女了嗎？
You know why I'll never see my wife and little girl again?
因為你奪走了她們的性命
'Cause you took 'em from me.
記得我嗎？
You remember me?
你當然記得
Sure you do.
你以前曾經去過我家
You came over to my house once before.
你不記得了？
You don't remember?
這河豚毒素…
This tetrodotoxin...
應該很好地進入你的體內了
should be nicely into your system by now.
這是從加勒比河豚魚的肝臟提取出來的
It's isolated from the liver of a Caribbean puffer fish.
所以它麻痹了你
So it paralyzes you,
但保留了其它神經功能
but leaves all the other neurological functions
…完好無損
perfectly intact.
換句話說，你沒法動彈了…
In other words, you can't move...
但你可以感覺到一切
but you feel everything.
它不會減輕你一丁點痛苦
It does absolutely nothing to blunt the pain.
而你即將體驗
And you're about to experience more of that
你根本無法想像到的
than you could ever fucking imagine.
這是止血帶
These are tourniquets
這樣你就不會流血 因為你可能要在這待上一陣
so you don't bleed out, 'cause you may be here a while.
生理鹽水…
Saline solution-
應該能讓我們繼續下去
that should keep us going.
綁上皮帶…安全牢固
Clamps- nice and secure.
舒服吧？
Comfortable?
你真的在發抖
You really are shaking.
確定你沒事？
Sure you're all right?
你會愛上這個的…
You'll love this-
腎上腺素
adrenaline.
現在注射這個，你就不會暈過去了
Now this is so you don't pass out.
來吧
There you go.
感覺怎樣？很好吧？
How's that feel? Good?
現在我可不希望你吞下你的舌頭
Now what we don't want is you swallowing your tongue,
所以陪著我吧
so bear with me.
這是為你的老二準備的 但我們稍後再做
Now this is for your penis, but we'll get to that later.
手術刀…
Scalpel...
割雙眼皮用的
for your eyelids,
萬一你中途他媽的閉上眼睛
in case you insist on fucking shutting them.
你瞧
You see,
我知道無助絕望的滋味
I know what it feels like to be helpless.
就如我看著你屠殺我全家一樣
just like when I watched you slaughter my whole family.
你知道你沒法跟天斗 對吧，多比？
You know you can't fight fate, right, Darby?
哦！
Oh!
你看… 我還特別為你準備了這個
And look- I made this especially for you.
喜歡麼？ 嗯，我不想讓你錯過一切
You like it? Yeah, I didn't want you to miss anything.
現在你處在屋裡最好的觀賞位置
Now you have the best view in the house.
你聽到了嗎？
You hear that?
你的心臟跳得很快
Your heart is beating so fast.
哦，我也是
No, me too.
好了
Okay.
現在她們能看到你受折磨了
Now they get to watch you suffer.
她們將是你最後看到的東西
They'll be the last thing you ever see
當我切斷你該死的四肢時
as I cut off every single one of your fucking limbs.
看，我沒撒謊
See, I wasn't lying
我說過我不希望你進監獄
when I told you that I wanted to keep you out of prison.
都是實話
That was the truth.
謝謝你的車
Thanks for the car.
好了，這是有關多比的所有案件檔案
Sarah: Okay, these are all the case files on Darby.
我盡力調查了 我們有犯罪現場的照片
I vetted through what I could. We have crime-scene photos-
不需要看了，嗯
Don't need to see 'em.
好的
Okay.
- 什麼事困擾你？ - 多比
- What's bothering you? - It's Darby.
他所犯的罪行都有一個共同點
All the crimes he's committed have one thing in common,
那就是暴力 但昨天行刑現場
and that was violence. But yesterday at that execution,
- 並非暴力，而是… - 是什麼？
- that wasn't violence. That was- - What?
- 是智力 - 好吧
- That was intellect. - Okay.
- 你在想什麼？ - 我也不知道
- What are you thinking? - I don't know.
我只是在想我們不應該再查多比
I'm just thinking maybe we shouldn't be looking for Darby.
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
瑞斯
Rice.
好消息，檢察官 找到多比了
Detective: Good news, Counselor. We found Darby.
不過我得說一句 還不如以前好看
I gotta say though, he's looked better.
他們發現他被肢解成25塊
Sarah: They found him in about 25 pieces:
沒有腿，沒有手臂 眼臉被割了…真可怕
no legs, no arms, eyelids were sliced off- gruesome.
- 為多比掉淚？ - 不至於
- Nick: Shedding tears for Darby? - Not quite.
- 我看到你眼睛打轉了 - 想想誰有動機
- Cantrell: I see your wheels turning. - Nick: Think motive- who has one?
那個丈夫、父親 我們對他瞭解多少？
Cantrell: The husband, the father. What do we know about him?
警方發現多比的那間倉庫是他的
He owned the warehouse where they found Darby.
- 還有呢？ - 他是一個工匠
- What else? - He's a tinkerer-
小發明家，發明了一些東西 他持有一些專利
uh, little inventions, gizmos. He holds two dozen patents
賺了不少錢
that made him some money.
幾年前，他賣了大部分財產
He liquidated most of his wealth a few years ago
買了些臨近機場、化學工廠
to buy some industrial properties around airports,
和鐵道場附近的院子
chemical plants, raiI yards.
- 這不合理 - 沒錯，很古怪，是吧？
- It doesn't add up. - No, it's weird, right?
全部都搜查，莎拉 看看能找到什麼
Search 'em all, Sarah. See what you find.
不許動！
Freeze!
- 跪下，快！ - 跪下！
- Get down, go! - On your knees!
- 臉朝下，臉朝下 - 把他按下去銬起來
- Face down, face down! - Pull him down and cuff him!
這個瘋子嚇到我了
Crazy men scare the shit out of me.
這傢伙是個律師嗎？
Detective: Is this guy a lawyer?
不
No.
他是一個工程師
He's an engineer.
尼克，看看這個 （美國法典：註釋版）
Sarah: Nick, look at this.
我們沒有半點證據 需要他坦白認罪
Cantrell: We have zero evidence. Gonna need a confession.
他來的路中有沒有給你們造成麻煩？
He give you any trouble on the way in?
不，沒有
No, nothing.
我們拿走他手鏈時，他不太高興
He wasn't too happy when we took his bracelet, though.
- 什麼事？ - 瑞斯家的包裹
- Can I help you? - Package for the Rice family.
哦，好的，謝謝
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
媽媽，我獨奏會的影帶送來了 我們可以看了嗎？
Mom, the video from my recital came. Can we watch it?
- 拜託啦？ - 不，現在不行
- Please? - No, not you.
不，我們說過要等爸爸回來一起看的 記得麼？
No, please, we said we were gonna wait for your father, remember?
- 拜託了？ - 不，現在不行
- Please? - No, not now.
好吧
Okay.
啊哈，好的
Uh-huh, yes.
好的，肯定的
Yes, absolutely.
媽媽！
Mommy!
別擔心，他只是在消除這傢伙的戒心 讓他放輕鬆些
Don't worry, he's just disarming the guy, letting him feeI easy.
我要跟你說的話 不希望有其他任何人聽見
What I'm about to tell you I don't want anybody else to hear.
身為檢察官，我現在要打破所有原則
As a prosecutor, I'm breaking all the rules right now,
我不管那一套 因為我是一個父親
and I don't give a damn because I'm a father.
我有個女兒
I have a little girl.
而你幹的…棒極了
And what you did... bravo.
沒有多比和阿米的世界會更美好
The world is better without Darby and Ames.
你不會看到我或我的人流一滴淚
You're not gonna see a tear shed from me or anybody in my office.
說完這些…
With that being said...
我該辦正事了
I have a job to do.
我將會問你一些非常簡單而直接的問題
I'm gonna ask you some very simple and direct questions.
我建議你也用同樣的方式回答
I suggest that you answer them in the same fashion.
你叫克萊德·亞歷山大·謝爾頓嗎？
Is your name Clyde Alexander Shelton?
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
而你已經放棄請律師的權利，對吧？
And you've waived your right to counsel, correct?
- 是的，先生 - 你確定你想這樣做嗎？
- Yes, sir. - You sure you want to do that?
是的
Yes.
是你謀殺了克拉倫斯·多比嗎
Did you murder Clarence Darby?
我想過要他死
I wanted him dead.
他殺了我的妻子和孩子
He killed my wife and child.
魯珀特… 你也殺了他嗎？
Rupert Ames- did you murder him as well?
魯珀特·阿米該死
Rupert Ames deserved to die.
他們都該死
They both deserved to die.
那麼你策劃過這兩起謀殺案？
So you arranged both of those murders?
恩，我計劃過…
Yes, I planned it...
在我的頭腦裡，一遍又一遍 花了很長的時間
in my head, over and over again. It took me a long time.
好吧
All right.
我想我們的對話結束了
I guess we're done here.
檢察官？
Counselor?
估計你要取消跟羅伯茨法官12點半的午餐了
You might want to canceI your 12:30 lunch with Judge Roberts.
什麼？
Excuse me?
實際上，你大概要取消本周餘下的行程了
In fact, you might want to cancel the rest of the week,
因為你會相當忙 坐下吧
'cause you're gonna be busy. Sit down.
我們這問完了 我們有了你的供詞
We're done here. We have your confession.
嗯，哦，完了？
Mmm. Oh, you do?
錄音帶裡
On tape.
瞧，在我們這行裡 我們稱那為「灌籃」
See, in our profession, we consider that a slam-dunk.
哦，真的嗎？ 我不認為，讓我們回想一下
Oh, really? I don't think so. Let's think back.
我說什麼了？
What did I say?
我說我想過克拉倫斯·多比死？
That I wanted to kill Clarence Darby?
是的，當然 哪個父親不想呢？
Yeah, sure. What father wouldn't?
多比和阿米都該死
That both Darby and Ames deserved to die?
我想大部分人都會認同那點
I think most people would agree with that.
我在腦子裡一遍又一遍地計劃過這件事
That I planned it over and over again in my head?
是呀，誰不會幻想那樣呢？
Yeah. Who wouldn't fantasize about that?
這些沒一句是承認罪行，尼克
None of these are an admission of guilt, Nick.
- 你或許想檢查一下帶子 - 我們知道是你幹的
- You might want to check the tape. - We know you did it.
可這與你知道什麼無關 而是你能在法庭上證明什麼
Well, it's not what you know, it's what you can prove in court.
這不是你曾跟我講過的話嗎？
Didn't you tell me that once?
你理論的唯一毛病是
The only problem with your theory
多比的屍體是在你名下土地上發現的
is that Darby's body was found on your property.
我名下許多土地中的一個… 一座老舊的廢棄倉庫，尼克
One of my many properties- an old abandoned warehouse, Nick.
吸毒者，他們常常擅自闖進去
Junkies, they trespass there all the time.
多比不會牽涉毒品交易嗎？
Isn't Darby involved in the drug trade?
那是一個沉淪的世界 我打賭陪審團會認同的
That's an unsavory world. I bet you a jury would agree.
或者某人試圖嫁禍於我
Or perhaps someone was trying to frame me.
知道吧，克萊德
You know, Clyde,
牢裡有很多混蛋自認為比我聰明
there's a lot of assholes in prison that thought they were smarter than me.
我們別再扯談了
Let's stop fucking around.
尼克，除非你有鐵證
Nick, unless you have any hard evidence,
否則我們為何在這？ 我們為何在這談話
then why are we even here? Why are we having this-
你想要什麼？
- What do you want? - -conversation?
好，很簡單
Well, that's easy.
現在你是那個和謀殺犯做交易的人了，對吧？
Now you're the one who makes deals with murderers, yeah?
那我就要提出我的條件了
So I've come to make mine.
我會給你一個坦白 一個真正的坦白
I will give you a confession, a reaI confession.
你只需要給我東西作為回報
You just have to give me something in return.
哦，好吧，你已經是個謀殺犯了 還想要什麼呢？
Yeah, well, since you are a murderer, what might that be?
一張床
A bed.
得是一張好床
But a nice bed.
我要給自己一張舒適的床
I want a nice new one for my cell.
很簡單
Very simple.
你一定得辦好 因為現在的床凹凸不平，尼克
You're gonna have to deal with that, because the one I have is lumpy, Nick.
快令我抓狂了
It's making me crazy.
克萊德，跟謹小慎微的人打交道讓我很煩
Clyde, I think you've got me confused with detail people.
所以，我不管你牢房裡的條件
See, I don't deaI with prison conditions.
我想牢房裡的床用螺絲固定住了
I believe those cots are bolted into the cells.
那就是扳手的作用，蠢驢
Well, that's what wrenches are for, dumbass.
你知道，有一種達西安娜床
You know, one of those new Duxiana beds
帶有調整…你知道 那種調整腰椎支撐的床吧
with the adjustable- you know, adjustable lumbar support,
- 就是那種 - 我看過那廣告
- that's the one. - I've seen the commercial.
- 我要的就是那種 - 那種床不錯
- That's the one I want. - Those are nice.
- 因為真的… - 夜裡晚些時候
- 'Cause really- - Comes on late at night.
- 坦白講我認為… - 兩個老年人躺在床上
- And frankly I don't think- - Two old people laying on the bed.
我沒法專注於任何事情
- I'll be able to focus on anything
除非在那張有療效的達西安那床上
untiI I've had a good revitalizing night's sleep
我晚上睡個安穩的好覺
in my therapeutic Duxiana bed.
這就是交易
So that's the deal:
你給我要的床 我就對你坦白
you get me my bed, you get your confession.
好吧，讓我考慮一下
Okay, let me think about that for a second.
這個怎麼樣…
How about...
他媽的不行
fuck no.
喂，你在幹嗎？
Hey, what are you doing?
- 什麼意思？ - 你為什麼拒絕他？
- What do you mean? - Why did you tell him no?
席夢思床？那不是他說的算的
A mattress? He doesn't make those kinds of decisions.
別太自我了，尼克 希爾頓說對了一點，這個案子沒證據
Take your ego out of it, Nick. Shelton's got a point: this case is shit.
我們需要他坦白 一張席夢思床換一個殺人犯的供詞
We need a confession. And a mattress for a murder confession?
- 這是個非常划算的買賣 - 他在耍我們，喬納斯
- That's a pretty good deal. - He's playing us, Jonas.
恩，接下來是我們玩他了
Well, then we will play him.
尼克?
Nick?
辦公室有急電找你 他們說你不接你手機
There's an urgent call from your office. They say you're not answering your cell.
我得打理完這裡的事情 然後盡快回家
I need to finish up here and then I will be home as soon as I can.
聽我說，這個錄影帶上的東西…
Listen to me: the things on this video-
尼克，我從未見過的…
Nick, I have never seen anything like it.
求你快點回家吧
Please come home.
聽著，你得冷靜下來 告訴她那不是真的…
Listen, you need to calm down. Tell her that it's not real...
- 好的 - 告訴她，我愛她
- Okay. - ... and that I love her.
回家吧，求你快點回家
Come home. Come home soon, please.
- 凱莉，你有看到他的臉嗎？ - 沒有
- Kelly, did you see his face? - No.
用東西遮住了 我看不到
It was covered with something. I couldn't see.
好的，寶貝，讓我忙完這邊 我就馬上回去了，好吧？
Okay, baby, let me finish up here and I'll come home as fast as I can, okay?
好的
Okay.
這個混蛋寄了一張他殺多比的DVD到我家裡
This motherfucker sent a DVD to my house of him killing Darby.
- 什麼? - 我女兒看到了
- What? - My daughter saw it.
他錄下來了？ 我們抓到他了
He recorded it? We've got him.
不，沒有，他帶著面具 我們需要他認罪
No no, he had on a mask. We need that confession.
你還想和這個人討價還價嗎？
You still want to bargain with this man?
典獄長，一切皆有可能
The art of the possible, Warden.
做這筆交易吧
Make the deal.
喂，來啊，哥們！也給我一張！
Man: Hey, come on, man! Give us one!
後背毛病，典獄長 最難受了
Back problems, Warden- the worst.
有比那嚴重的問題
You got bigger problems than that.
所有人都沒有的東西，孩子
It's the have-nots in here, son.
換了是我，我知道我可不想有
I don't know that I want to be the one "have. "
轉身
Turn around.
我認為他不喜歡我
I don't think he likes me.
床不錯
Nice bed.
謝謝
Thank you.
是單人的
It's a single.
我要在這小心我的後背了，聽到了嗎？
I'd watch my fucking back around here, you hear?
進監房，去吧
In the cell, let's go.
我們到處都找不到克萊德·謝爾頓的馬腳
We can't put Clyde Shelton anywhere-
工作中，城市裡，甚至整個國家都沒有
not in a job, not in a city, not even the country.
所以我深挖了一下 從他失蹤的幾年裡我發現了些事情
So I dug a little deeper and I found something from his missing years:
國防部有兩筆契約款匯給了克萊德
a couple of contract payments to Clyde from the Department of Defense.
- 他的不動產呢？ - 他買了九處不動產
- And his real estate? - He bought nine properties
登記在他的名下 然後他將這些資產…
under his own name, then he transferred them
轉到巴拿馬的某間公司
to some corporation in Panama.
由於缺乏互助條款，
We can't get to the addresses.
我們無法得到地址
A lack of reciprocity is our problem.
我們繞了個圈又回到了農舍
So I'm gonna circle back to the farmhouse.
那是浪費時間 他本來就想讓我們找到他在那裡
That's a waste of time. He wanted us to find it and find him there.
那些工業用品倒令人感興趣
It's the industrial stuff that's curious.
好了，我不管你們要做什麼 或著你們要得罪誰
All right, I don't care what you have to do and who you have to piss off.
如果我們得再次入侵巴拿馬，好吧
If we have to invade Panama again, fine.
克萊德隱藏這些財產是有理由的 給我找出來
Clyde is hiding those properties for a reason. Find him.
明白
Got it.
- 寶貝，你有留了一條縫嗎？ - 嗯？是的，我留了一條縫
- Baby, you leave it cracked? - Hmm? Yeah, I left it cracked.
- 夜燈呢？ - 她這麼大了還開夜燈是不是…？
- Night light? - Isn't she too old for a night light?
嗯，我開夜燈了
Yeah, I left a night light.
- 很好 - 聽著
- Good. - Look,
我告訴她視頻不是真的
I told her that that video wasn't real.
- 好 - 那只是恐怖片
- Okay. - It's some sort of horror film-
某種她不該看的恐怖片
something she shouldn't be looking at anyway.
- 好，很好 - 她會沒事的
- Okay, good. - She'll be okay.
嗯，那你呢？
Yeah. And you?
- 我怎樣？好嗎？ - 是的
- Am I what? Okay? - Yeah.
當然，我看起來像有事麼？
Of course. Don't I look okay?
- 嗯？ - 嗯
- Hmm? - Yeah.
尼克總是沒事的
Nick is always okay.
我總是非常好
Always- I'm extra good.
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你
I love you too.
鑒於謝爾頓先生的經濟狀況
In light of Mr. Shelton's economic means
和潛在的逃亡風險
and his potential flight risk,
加上阿米和多比先生死於非命
the egregious nature of both Mr. Ames's and Mr. Darby's deaths,
請求將保釋駁回，法官閣下
the state requests that bail be denied, Your Honor.
謝爾頓先生，既然你放棄了你律師的權利
Judge: Seeing as how you've...
你有什麼想說的？
waived your right to counsel, Mr. Shelton,
do you have anything to say?
謝爾頓先生？
Mr. Shelton?
你有任何話想說嗎？謝爾頓…
Do you have anything that you'd like to say, Mr. Shelton?
是的，是的，是的，法官閣下
Yes yes yes, Your Honor.
- 我用站起來嗎？ - 請吧
- Should I stand? - Please.
法官閣下，我是一個守法公民
Your Honor, I'm a law-abiding citizen.
只是一個平凡的人
I'm just a regular guy.
我不是一個會逃跑的人
I am not a flight risk.
這是我第一次被控違法
And this is my first alleged offense.
而且檢方沒有呈出任何一樣對我不利的證據
And the prosecution has not presented one single piece of evidence against me.
在此情況下
Now in these circumstances,
除非檢方找到了新的情報
unless the state has obtained some new piece of information
關於我牽涉到目前討論的案子
relating to my involvement in the matter in question,
否則我會覺得扣押我並不准保釋
then I find it highly prejudiciaI, even constitutionally offensive,
是種很嚴重的偏見
to keep me detained without bail.
這是一種倒退，法官閣下
It's a slippery slope, Your Honor.
難道我們沒見過這種暴行的後果嗎
Haven't we seen the result of such violations,
不管是在國內還是國外
both internationally and domestically? Case in point
比如戴夫-麥唐納案子 檔案編號041325
would be Day v. McDonough, docket #041325.
我事實上…傾向於同意你，謝爾頓先生
I am actually inclined to agree with you, Mr. Shelton.
法官閣下，謝爾頓先生已經同意 向我們認罪了
Your Honor, Mr. Shelton has agreed to give us a full confession.
他已經認罪了嗎？瑞斯先生
Has he given it, Mr. Rice?
沒有，法官閣下
No, Your Honor.
那麼就我看來
Well, then in my opinion,
檢方沒有令人信服的證據
the state has failed to establish a compelling basis
來限制他的行動自由 我將同意保釋，保釋金為…
for its motion, and I will grant bail in the amount of-
法官閣下 我想提醒您別這樣做
Your Honor, I would caution you not to do that.
謝謝
Thank you.
什麼？
Excuse me?
不，我想我不會為你開脫的
No, I don't think I will excuse you.
你瞧我說的意思是
You see, this is what I'm talking about.
你剛剛準備放我走 你在開玩笑嗎？
You were about to let me go. Are you kidding me?
我們在這裡最開始是為什麼
This is why we're here in the first place.
你以為我不記得你是誰了，夫人？
You think I don't remember who you are, lady?
謝爾頓先生，我會小心謹慎地
I would tread carefully, Mr. Shelton.
哦，那麼我該如何小心謹慎？
Well, how carefully should I tread?
因為顯然地我剛殺了兩個人
Because apparently I just killed two people,
而你卻準備讓我走出那道門！
and you were about to let me walk right out that door!
你是多麼誤導別人？
How misguided are you?
我隨便拿出一兩個合法的案例唬你
I feed you a couple of bullshit legal precedents,
你就…你就像個火辣的婊子一樣撲過來
and there you go- you jump on it like a bitch in heat.
- 朋友們，你們都窩在… - 我警告你，謝爾頓先生
- Folks, you all hang out- - I'm warning you, Mr. Shelton!
- 同一個小俱樂部裡 - 你會被控訴藐視法庭
- -in the same little club. - You will be held in contempt!
每天你讓瘋子和謀殺犯回到大街上
And every day you let madmen and murderers back on the street.
- 你太忙於教條判案 - 再次警告！
- You're too busy treating the law- - One more time!
- 就像該死的生產線一樣 - 再次警告！
- -like it's a fucking assembly line! - One more time.
- 你知道什麼叫公正嗎？ - 你現在…
- Do you have any idea what justice is? - You are now-
- 不管什麼是對與錯！ - 被控以藐視法庭！
- Whatever happened to right and wrong? - -in contempt of court.
- 不管什麼是對與錯！ - 把他押下去！
- Whatever happened to right and wrong? - Remove this man.
- 不管別人發生什麼！ - 保釋駁回！
- Whatever happened to the people? - Bail denied!
- 不管什麼公正！ - 保釋駁回！
- Whatever happened to justice? - Bail denied!
我打賭你都把它塞在屁眼裡了
And I bet you take it up the fucking ass, bitch.
法警！
Bailiff.
嗨，待會見，尼克
Clyde: Hey, see you later, Nick.
精神失常？
Nick: Insanity?
那就是你自我辯護的伎倆嗎？ 精神失常？
That's what you're building your defense on? Insanity?
尼克，我告訴過你我會向你坦白
Nick, I told you I would give you a confession.
而我…是認真的
And I- I meant it.
- 我今天看了部電影 - 你看了？
- I saw a movie today. - You did?
我女兒也看了同一個
My daughter saw the same movie.
你告訴你女兒這是關於好人對壞人的麼？
Well, you taught your daughter about good versus eviI?
沒必要
I don't have to.
嗯，那部電影的主題就是邪不勝正
Well, that's what this movie was about: good conquering evil,
正義伸張 邪惡受懲
the righteous prospering, the wicked suffering.
我不明白
I didn't get that.
我會再給你一次機會，克萊德
I'm gonna give you one more chance, Clyde.
別考驗我，因為我會跟你死耗
And don't test me 'cause I will run you over.
很公平
Fair enough.
你的確給了我要的床
You did get me my bed.
交易就是交易
A deal's a deal.
錄影帶上是你殺了克拉倫斯·多比 對嗎？
That was you on video killing Clarence Darby, wasn't it?
是的，那是我
Yes, that was me.
好了，很公平 那是我，克萊德·謝爾頓
Okay, fair enough. That was me, Clyde Shelton,
錄像裡的人，殺死克拉倫斯·多比
on the video, killing Clarence Darby.
不夠，克萊德，我需要細節
Not good enough, Clyde. I need specifics.
我用斷線鉗鉗斷他的手指
I took his fingers with bolt cutters,
用尖嘴鉗剪斷他的腳趾頭
his toes with tin snips,
用鋼鋸鋸下他的蛋蛋
his balls with a hacksaw,
用箱刀割下他的老二
and his penis with a box cutter.
這樣夠詳細了吧？
How's that for specifics?
阿米呢？
And Ames?
調換筒罐很容易 今天一切都是自動化的
Switching the canisters was easy. Everything's automated these days,
我只需要入侵貨運公司的服務器
so I just hacked into the shipping company's server
篡改幾個數字，包裹就來到我這兒了
and swapped a few numbers around so the package came to me.
然後我用某種更有內涵的東西
Then I switched the potassium chloride
調換了…氯化鉀
with something a little more... deliberate.
好了，我聽夠了你的狗屎
Well, I'm tired of hearing your bullshit.
我得到我想要的了
I got everything I need.
現在怎麼辦？
What now?
我回家，你進監獄
I go home; you go to prison.
你知道 正義必將伸張，邪惡必受罰
You know, the righteous prospering, the wicked suffering.
那應該會令你對司法體制感覺好些
That ought to make you feel better about the system.
如果我有其它要坦白的呢？
What if I had another confession to make?
向神父說吧
Call a priest.
可另一個坦白需要另一個交易，尼克
But another confession would mean another deal, Nick,
所以你必須給我點東西作為回報
so you would have to give me something in return.
你曾去過德菲斯可餐廳嗎？ 他們送外賣
You ever been to Del Frisco's? They cater.
所以午餐我想吃20盎司的牛排
So for lunch, I would love a 20oz porterhouse steak,
五分熟，或許有點焦
medium, maybe a little bit charred,
加上一堆的配菜… 薯條、蘆筍、奶油南瓜
with all the trimmings- pommes frites, asparagus, butter squash.
去你的，去你的薯條
Fuck you and your pommes frites.
我還要告訴你，可以把我的iPod拿來麼？
I'll tell you what: can I have my iPod as well?
我喜歡用餐時來點音樂
I'd love a little bit of music with my meal.
談判的首條原則，克萊德 你得有談判的資本
First rule of negotiating, Clyde: you gotta have something to bargain with.
比爾·雷諾斯的命足夠嗎？
Would the life of Bill Reynolds suffice?
打開
Open it.
這該死的比爾·雷諾斯是誰？
Who the fuck is Bill Reynolds?
多比的律師
Darby's attorney.
跟我說你有他的下落了
Tell me you located him.
我聯繫上他妻子了 她三天前報案說他失蹤了
I've got his wife. She reported him missing three days ago.
謝謝你，雷諾斯太太
Thank you, Mrs. Reynolds.
看來我終究還是有資本還價的，尼克
Clyde: Well, looks like I got something to bargain with after all, Nick.
現在比爾·雷諾斯依然活著
At the moment, Bill Reynolds is still alive.
我會告訴你他的確切位置
I'll tell you exactly where he is.
只要把我的午餐和音樂1點整帶來
Just bring me my meal and my music at 1:00 exactly.
正好1點
00 sharp.
1點，尼克
00, Nick.
好，就停在那
That's good, right there.
好了，起來
All right, up!
- 已經12點55了 - 我不聽命於他或者你
- It's 5 to 1:00. - I don't take orders from him or you.
囚犯不知道時間
And inmates don't have access to the time.
- 我們告訴他們幾點就是幾點 - 我不關心他是否有勞力士
- We tell them what time it is. - I don't care if he has a Rolex or not.
我們得遵守時間 我們答應過的時間
We need to stick to the timeline that was agreed to.
去他媽的，尼克，讓他等
Fuck him, Nick. Let him wait.
老天，他鋸掉了那傢伙的老二
Christ, he sawed a guy's dick off.
不管你喜歡與否 我們要遵守他的時間
Whether you like it or not, we are on his time.
再檢查一遍
Check it again.
你們就這麼噁心我嗎！
Inmate: Are you shitting me with this?!
這混蛋
This motherfucker!
快點！ 我快餓死了！
Man, come on! I'm fucking hungry!
蒸蘆筍
Steamed asparagus,
- 龍蝦通心粉和奶酪 - 喔
- lobster macaroni and cheese... - Wow.
上等腰肉牛排 焦的，五成熟
...porterhouse steak, seared, medium rare.
嗯！
Mmm!
嗯
Hmm.
- 餐巾紙，尼克 - 餐巾紙
- Napkin, Nick. - Napkin.
哦，麻煩你了，服務生
Oh, excuse me, waiter?
你拿百分之三十做小費
You might want to put 30% down for yourself, my man.
- 喂，幾點了？ - 1點了
- Hey, what time is it? - It's 1:00.
時間對嗎，尼克？
Is that right, Nick?
- 1點08分 - 真讓人失望，典獄長
- It's 1:08. - That's disappointing, Warden.
我是說，如果你們都對我不實在
I mean, how can you expect me not to fuck with you
怎能保證我不耍你們呢
when you can't even be honest with me?
克萊德，你要的事情都辦到了 現在，雷諾斯在哪？
Late or not, Clyde, you have what you asked for. Now where's Reynolds?
紳士們，我能拿個銀製餐具嗎？
Can I have some silverware, gentlemen?
銀製餐具
Silverware.
給你一隻叉匙
You get a spork.
白癡
Idiot.
謝謝
Thanks.
好了，克萊德
Come on, Clyde.
好吧
Okay.
我們來吧
Here we go:
北緯39度57分04
39N57'...04",
東經75度10分22
075W10'22".
你最好快點，尼克
And you'd better hurry, Nick.
因為除了典獄長的時間 其他人的時間已經晚了
'Cause by anybody's watch but the warden's, you're already late.
- 開門 - 混蛋們，我的午餐呢？
- Open the door! - Inmate: Where's my lunch?
我帶一支地面小隊過去
I'll take a ground unit!
我猜如果我不跟你分享這個的話 你會…
So I suppose if I don't share this with you, you're gonna-
我會他媽站起來
I'm gonna get the fuck up,
舉起我的右手
I'm gonna cock back my right hand,
把你的腦瓜劈成兩半，那樣如何？
and I'm gonna split your whole fucking skull in two. How about that?
好的，快過來一起吧 東西多著呢
Well, come on over here. Join me. There's plenty to go around.
這裡，好好吃 來點意大利面
Here, enjoy. Have some pasta.
味道很好
It's good.
要不要來點牛排 你喜歡牛排吧？
What about some steak? You want steak?
- 嗯 - 這，來點牛排
- Mmm. - Here, have some steak.
這一大塊都是你的
Here's a big piece for you.
給你
There you go.
不錯，哈？
Good, huh?
你到底因為什麼進來的？
What'd you do to get in here, anyways?
我做了我應該做的事
I did what I had to do.
你搞了個妞還是什麼？
So you got a girl or something?
嗯，說來話長
Mmm, it's a long story.
駕駛員，還要多久？
Pilot, how much longer?
預計時間兩分鐘
Two minutes.
你呢？搞了個妞？
How about you? You have a girl?
- 在家裡搞了好幾個妞 - 哦，是嗎？
- Got a few girls back home. - Oh, yeah?
是的
Yeah.
- 你在這沒有男朋友吧？ - 滾蛋吧
- You have a boyfriend in here or no? - Get the fuck out of here.
這是，這是雷諾斯的
This is- it's Reynolds's.
- 看來情況不妙 - 快挖
- Not a good sign, Nick. - Just dig.
- 上帝！ - 雷諾斯
- Jesus Christ! - Reynolds!
- 他失去意識了 - 雷諾斯
- He's unconscious. - Reynolds!
他死了，尼克 他死了
He's gone, Nick. He's gone.
氧氣罩？
- Oxygen? - Get something to get him out!
- 找東西把他弄出來
Detective: He's got IV lines going to his-
他把他銬住了
He's got him cuffed!
你有開手銬的鑰匙嗎？
Nick: Listen, you got your keys to the cuffs?
- 嗯！ - 嗯！
- Mmm! - Mmm.
媽的
Shit.
哦，上帝，吃的真爽
Oh, God, I'm so happy.
你的幸運日，啊？ 有東西吃
Your lucky day, huh? Get some food.
這裡，要拍張照嗎？
Here, wanna take a shot at this?
- 這是什麼？ - 知道怎麼用嗎？
- What is it? - Know how to use it?
不知道
No.
哦，該死，快看
Inmate: Oh, shit! Check this out!
他瘋了
He's crazy!
現在別停下，夥計
Don't stop now, partner!
幹掉他，快！ 把他頭割下來
Finish him, come on! Take his head off!
割下來
Take it off!
我需要洗個澡，典獄長
I need a shower, Warden.
把他弄出去
Get him out of there!
唐尼根，你的表幾點了？
Nick: Dunnigan, what time do you have?
1點37分
37.
到這裡我們大約花了15分鐘
Took us roughly 15 minutes to get here.
是嗎？
Yeah?
雷諾斯的氧氣被設定在1點15分關閉
Reynolds's air was rigged to shut off at 1:15.
如果謝爾頓能準時吃到午餐 他應該能活著
If Shelton would have got his lunch on time, he'd still be alive.
去他媽的，尼克
Fuck this guy, Nick.
他想要玩遊戲 我們也可以跟他玩
He wants to play games, we can play games too.
我們得把手套摘下來
We need to take the gloves off.
不行
No.
尼克，我是莎拉 聽著，克萊德殺了他的牢友
Nick, it's Sarah. Listen, Clyde murdered his cell-mate.
典獄長大發雷霆，要把他移至禁閉室
The warden is furious. He's moving him to solitary.
目前我就只知道這些
That's all I know right now.
目前什麼情況？
How are we doing?
不錯，你能相信嗎？
Great. Can you believe this?
把他iPod拆了找線索
Checking his iPod for clues.
我對我女兒也這麼做
I do the same thing with my daughter's.
有收穫嗎？
Learn anything?
恩，他們都聽垃圾音樂
Yeah, they both got shit taste in music.
我們有招術跟這個傢伙玩了嗎？
We got a game plan with this guy or what?
招術？
Game plan?
我跟你說，我有個招術
I tell you, I got a game plan.
給我跟他五分鐘時間 我會搞殘這個混蛋
Give me five minutes alone with him and I'll cripple the fucker.
我才不管他家庭發生了什麼
I don't give a shit what happened to his family.
沒有借口
It's no excuse.
哇
Wow.
就在這
Stop right there.
進屋去
Step into the cell.
我們發現雷諾斯了
We found Reynolds.
當趕到時太遲了
Moments too late, from what I hear.
我必須打給他老婆 告訴她丈夫被活埋了
I had to call his wife and tell her that her husband had been buried alive.
司法制度需要嚴厲，尼克
Justice should be harsh, Nick,
尤其是對於那種對他人拒絕公正的人
but especially for those who denied it to others.
殺你的牢友呢？怎麼回事？
And your cell-mate? What was that about?
你殺死這人就是因為午餐來遲了
You murdered a man because your lunch was late.
不
No.
不，不，是你殺了他 因為你沒有信守承諾
No. No, you murdered him because you couldn't keep your word.
我們達成了協議，你和我 下午1點
We made a deal, you and I: 00 PM.
那是一個非常重要的原則 我希望你能開始學會，尼克
That's a pretty important principle I'd like you start learning, Nick:
- 遵守你的諾言 - 哦，真的嗎？
- keeping your word. - Oh, really?
當你折磨並殺死那些人時 你又在按什麼原則行事
What principle was at work when you tortured and killed those people?
那就是每個人都應該為自己的行為負責
That everyone must be held accountable for their actions.
你以為你的妻子女兒 對你以她們的名義殺人
You think your wife and daughter would feel good
會感覺很好嗎？
about you killing in their name?
我妻子和女兒再也沒有感覺了
My wife and daughter can't feeI anything.
他們死了
They're dead.
嘿，尼克
Hey, Nick?
查克萊德的不動產一事 史坦菲德法官拒絕了我們
On Clyde's real estate, Judge Stansfield shut us down.
他在尋找某個合法案例 我不知道是否存在
He's looking for some sort of legal precedent that I'm not sure exists.
- 但？ - 但…
- But? - But...
我想我可能找到了其它方法
I think I may have found a way around it.
- 我要找一個朋友幫忙 - 你的朋友是誰？
- I'll call in a favor from a friend. - Who's your friend?
不能透露朋友的名字 不然他們不會幫忙
You don't name your friends or they stop doing you favors.
坎特雷爾還說了什麼
Something else Cantrell said.
沒有，就這些了 喬納斯，你好
No, that was all you. Jonas, hi.
她思考的模式和你一樣，尼克 我看你把她訓練得很不錯
She's thinking just like you, Nick. Guess you trained her well.
- 有天她會坐上我的位子 - 我們透透氣去吧
- One day she'll have my job. - Let's get some air.
克萊德的政府契約款困擾著我
Clyde's government contract payments were bothering me,
因此我動用了一些舊關係 我們要見個人
so I pulled some ancient strings. We're meeting someone.
會是誰呢？
Who might that be?
那些做真正下流事情的人 所以我們才能夠住著美國夢
Someone who does some really nasty shit so we can live the American dream.
那麼克萊德終於瘋了嗎？
So Clyde finally lost it?
一定是有人真的惹毛他了
Somebody must have really pissed him off.
你和謝爾頓一起工作過？對吧？
You worked with Shelton, is that right?
首先，我從沒來過這裡 我們也從沒有對過話
Okay, first of all, I was never here and we never spoke.
告訴我們在對付誰 謝爾頓是間諜還是…
Tell us what we're dealing with. Shelton was a spy or-
間諜太稀鬆平常了 我就是間諜
Spies are a dime a dozen. I'm a spy.
克萊德是天才 他是會動腦筋那個
Clyde is a brain. He's a think-tank type guy.
他的專長是低速衝擊動力操作
His specialty was low-impact kinetic operations.
這是他殺人一種美化的說法嗎？
Is this a hell of a fancy way to say that he kills people?
我們殺人
We kill people.
他可以不共處一室就能幹出來
He figured out how to do it without ever being in the same room.
這是他的天賦，而且他是最優秀的
It was his gift, and he was the best.
有次我們對付一個狡猾的目標
One time we're tasking this tricky target.
我們用巡航導彈、猛禽戰機
I mean, we're using cruise missiles and predators
甚至動用了B2隱形轟炸機 飛到這傢伙的別墅去炸他
and we even had a B-2 bomber flatten this guy's villa with a JDAM.
我們循規蹈矩的方法浪費了數百萬
All right? We're burning up millions in ordnance
連這傢伙的影子都沒有見到
and we're getting nowhere with this guy.
所以我們找來了克萊德 請他解決這個問題
So we call Clyde and we ask him to solve our problem.
克萊德發明一項高強力縫線
Clyde develops a Kevlar thread
有著碳纖維制的高科技制輪裝置
with a high-tech ratchet made of carbon fiber
能夠安裝在領帶裡
put in a necktie.
兩天後，壞蛋太太回到家
Two days later, Mrs. Bad Guy comes home,
發現壞蛋先生倒在浴室的瓷磚上
finds Mr. Bad Guy dead on the bathroom tile,
窒息而死
choked to death.
我所說的是，只能假設這傢伙可以
What I'm saying is, just assume that this guy can hear and see
聽到或看到你的一舉一動
everything that you're doing.
不，我們把他關起來了 高度戒備中
Nick: No, we've got him locked away, maximum security.
如果他在監獄，那是因為他想在獄中
Man: If he's in jail, it's because he wants to be in jail.
他是個天生的戰略家 他的每個行動都有意義
He's a born tactician. Every move that he makes, it means something.
他殺死牢友，你以為是隨意的嗎？
That cell-mate that he killed- you think that was random?
不是
No.
那只是棋盤上被擺佈的一個棋子
That's a pawn being moved off the board.
換作我，我會找出下一個目標
If I were you, I'd be looking for the next piece.
和那案子有關聯的每個人
Anybody who had anything to do with that case,
他不會放過你們的
he's gonna be coming after you.
那你的意思是？ 你是說我們無法阻止他？
So what are you saying? You saying we can't stop him?
走進他的牢房 給他腦袋一顆子彈
Walk into his cell and put a bullet in his head.
除此之外？ 別無他法，你無法阻止他
Aside from that? No, you can't stop him.
如果克萊德想要你死，你就死
If Clyde wants you dead, you're dead.
- 你好 - 莎拉？莎拉，是尼克
- Hello? - Sarah? Sarah, it's Nick.
安排和伯奇法官會個面
Set up a meeting with Judge Burch.
我們得讓她幫我們把克萊德監押起來
We need her to help us keep Clyde on ice.
幫我們做什麼？尼克 他已經在牢裡了
Help us with what, Nick? The man's in prison.
他比我們想像的更可怕
He's worse than we thought.
- 切斯特是你的男朋友，對吧？ - 切斯特
- Chester's your boyfriend, right? - Chester.
是的
Yeah.
很好，也許去他那待幾天
Good. Maybe stay a few days at his place.
再叫唐尼派輛巡邏車到我家來
And have Dunnigan send a patroI car to my house.
對此很抱歉，莎拉
Sorry about this, Sarah.
我不能取代刑法
Judge Burch: I can't supersede the penal code.
你們已經把他關入禁閉室
You've already got him in solitary.
到下周隨便一個律師助理就會讓他出來
A half-decent paralegal will have him out of there by next week.
我們只想限制他的選擇
We just want to limit his options;
減少他的聯繫，減少渠道
give him less contact, less access,
即使只是解除他一個星期的委託權
even if it's just rescinding his mandatory exercise period for a week.
- 用什麼名義？ - 什麼都可以
- Under what cause? - Whatever cause you want.
隨便用什麼法條
Wrap it around whatever piece of legal doctrine
只要能合理化這個即可，法官大人
that helps you rationalize it, Your Honor.
那麼，我直說吧
So let me get this straight:
你們想要我侵犯上帝賦予他的權利？
you want me to violate his God-given civil rights
以某種罪惡第六感的名義
in the name of some murky sense of the greater good.
先生們，是這個意思嗎？
Is that the gist of it, gentlemen?
好吧，我入伙
Okay. I'm game.
只是別想持續太久，好嗎？
Just don't plan on it sticking for long, all right?
等會，你要接電話？
Wait, you're gonna take that,
你訓斥過我接電話的事情
after all the grief you've given me over cell phones?
那是當法官的好處之一，瑞斯先生
That's one of the benefits of being a judge, Mr. Rice.
我相當可以隨心所欲
I can pretty much do whatever I want.
喂？
Hello?
哦，上帝
Oh my God.
退後，退後
Nick: Back out. Back out.
…在市政廳，儘管還無法證實這些細節
Female reporter:... at city hall, though we are unable to confirm the details,
但我們知道至少一人死亡
we do know that at least one person is dead
官方稱很可能是謀殺
in what officials are calling a possible murder.
我們會有記者繼續…
We have reporters on the ground...
上來
Up.
有人在幫這傢伙
Somebody's helping this guy-
手機裡的炸彈 而她毫不知情
a bomb in that phone, and she doesn't know about it.
誰能做到呢？
Who had access?
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
我是戰爭裡過來的，還有兩個前妻 我沒事的
I've survived the war and two ex-wives. I'll be fine.
你還好嗎？
How are you holding up?
我還好
I'm good.
現在你把法官也殺了？
So you're killing judges now?
以我的經驗來看，尼克 只有血的教訓才能持久
In my experience, Nick, lessons not learned in blood are soon forgotten.
復仇能讓你在晚上得到溫暖嗎
And vengeance keeps you warm at night.
復仇？
Vengeance?
這就是你所認為的嗎？復仇？
That's what you think this is about? Vengeance?
還會是什麼呢？
What else could it be?
不，尼克，我有10年的時間可以復仇 如果我要做的話
No, Nick, I had 10 years for vengeance, if that's what I wanted.
你沒意識到我每天早上八點看你上班？
You don't think that I watch you go to work every morning at 8:00 AM?
或者看著凱莉帶丹尼斯8點15去上學？
Or that I watch Kelly take Denise to schooI, 8:15?
不，我可以在任何時候毀了你和你的家庭
No, I could have slaughtered you or your family anytime I wanted!
你甚至想過碰我的家人…
You even think about touching my family-
you even think about touching my family...
我是做我的工作
I do my job.
我是做的最出色的
I'm the best at it.
- 做的不錯 - 你在做你的工作？
- It works. - You were doing yourjob
以對你有利的方式，尼克 對你有利的方式
the way that best served you, Nick- the way that best served you.
- 這點得改變了 - 你想怎樣，克萊德？
- That has to change. - What do you want, Clyde?
你在和整個世界作戰？ 這不會令任何人退卻
You at war with the whole world? It's not gonna bring anybody back.
不，我在和這個…
No, I'm at war with this-
這個…這個破爛的玩意作戰
this- this broken thing-
把你和我連在一起的玩意
this thing that brought you and I together.
這爛玩意對神經正常的人有用
This broken thing works for people that are sane.
你以為你在做的事情能夠改變任何事情嗎？
You think doing what you're doing is gonna change anything?
你和其它幫助你的人
You and whoever else you have helping you
都要付出代價
are gonna pay.
我認為你並不知道誰在幫我 或我在做什麼？
I don't think you have any idea who's helping me or what I'm doing.
遲早的事
It's a matter of time.
看，你看過屍體 你見到煙霧
See, you see the bodies, you see the smoke,
可還有更大的場面等著你
but the larger picture still eludes you.
說說看
Do tell.
我很想說…
I would like to...
但我選擇演給你看
but I would rather show you.
我仍然對你有信念 所以我會給你最後一次機會
I still have faith in you, so I'm gonna give you one last chance.
這交易是
Here's the deal:
釋放我，並在早上六點前撤銷所有的指控
release me and drop all charges by 6:00 AM.
- 早上六點，尼克 - 不然怎樣？
- 6:00 AM, Nick. - Or what?
不然我殺了每個人
Or I kill everyone.
- 你好？ - 莎拉
- Hello? - Nick: Yeah, Sarah,
他一定有同夥 可能就是牢裡的某個人
he has to have an accomplice- probably somebody inside the prison.
我們必須調查所有犯人的檔案 看能否找出某種關聯
We have to go through all the prisoners' files to find some sort of connection.
檔案要送到辦公室嗎？
Do you want the files brought to the office?
不，沒時間了 叫大家一起到監獄來
No, there isn't time. Get everybody together and bring them to the prison.
我們要進駐
We're moving in.
別再看表了
Stop looking at your watch.
你朋友那邊有消息嗎？
Anything from your friend?
與巴拿馬那邊的條款很棘手
This treaty with Panama is a mess.
我們無法得到任何有關財產持有的記錄
We can't access anything about specific property holdings,
不過我朋友發現了一個後門
but my friend found this tiny loophole
可以瀏覽克萊德公司開銷記錄
that grants us access to Clyde's corporate expenses.
有用麼？
Does that help?
那麼對比下費城出售過的工業資產價格
So we match sale prices of industrial properties sold in Philly
和他公司所購買過的物品金額
up against purchases made by his corporation.
我知道了
Okay, I got it.
- 嘿，尼克，我能問你點事嗎？ - 嗯？
- Hey, Nick, can I ask you something? - Hmm?
你現在會做同樣的選擇嗎？
Would you do it the same way now?
你仍會幫多比達成協議嗎？
Would you still cut a deal for Darby?
這是工作呀，莎拉 我們得做出選擇
This is the job, Sarah. We have to make choices.
- 但你做出正確選擇了嗎？ - 我們的選擇正確，對吧？
- But did you make the right choice? - We made the right choice, right?
我不知道
I don't know.
我35歲了，尼克
I'm 35, Nick.
有許多東西…許多的可能性
And there are things- there are possibilities
是我現在無法擁有的
that I'm not gonna have now.
沒關係，我知道這是交易的一部分
And it's okay. I know it's part of the deal.
別誤會我 我喜歡為你工作
And don't get me wrong. I love working for you.
但我只想弄清楚我放棄的那些東西
But I just want to make sure I gave up those things
不光是為了高定罪率
for more than just a high conviction rate.
你要喝咖啡嗎？
Do you want any more coffee?
不
No.
好了
All right.
好了，我們集中精神 這人不是神僊
All right, let's just get focused here. This guy's not God.
他不是萬能的 他只是準備充分而已
He's not the All Powerful. He's just well-prepared.
我們也需要準備充分
We need to be equally well-prepared.
回家休息一兩個小時 然後回來重新開始
Take a couple of hours, go home, come back. We'll get a fresh start.
好嗎？
Okay?
過來，老人家 看我們能否給你買到早餐
Man: Come on, old man, let's see if we can find you some breakfast.
嘿，尼克，去休息一會吧
Hey, Nick, get some rest.
待我問候切斯特 我幾時才能見到他？
Give Chester my regards. When do I get to meet him?
哦，還不到那個時候
Oh, he's not ready for that.
晚安，瓊納斯
'Night, Jonas.
我不知道這個案子的結果會怎樣，尼克
I don't know how this one's gonna turn out, Nick.
我們得阻止他 那就是結果
We're gonna stop him. That's how it's gonna turn out.
啊！
Ahh!
莎拉
Sarah.
在過去的48個小時中 6名司法部的官員
Reporter: In the past 48 hours, six officials from the Justice Department
死於一連串的有預謀的襲擊中
have been killed in a series of vicious and premeditated attacks.
這還是美國歷史上的第一次
This marks the first time in the history of the United States
很顯然政府官員在被系統性地謀殺
where government officials have been, by all appearances,systematically murdered.
我們會繼續跟進事件的發展 為你帶來最新最細的報道…
We'll continue to follow this story and bring you up-to-the-minute details...
尼克，很抱歉我現在不得不這樣做 但我們在這裡找到了些東西
Nick, I'm sorry to have to do this now, but we've got something here.
就在牆外發現了這個…
Found this right outside the wall-
無線電裝置
radio beacon-
當人通過大門時 發送信號給車上的炸彈
sent an arming signal to the car bombs when they went through the gate.
警衛說他們抵達這前 檢查過每一輛車
Dunnigan: Security said they checked every car before anybody got in them.
他們沒有檢查油箱 大概那些奸鳥會放那裡
They didn't check the gas tanks. That's where the clever prick put 'em.
也是個精密的玩意
Real precise stuff too.
如果他想，可以幹掉更多的人
Could have taken out a lot more if he wanted to.
- 尼克的車呢？ - 怪就怪在這裡
- Cantrell: What about Nick's car? - That's the weird thing.
他的車子沒問題 沒被做過手腳
It's clean- hadn't been touched.
我得走了
I gotta go.
天呀
Woman: Jesus Christ.
請迴避下
Privacy, please.
那讓我直說吧
So let me get this straight:
我們不光知道誰幹的
not only do we know who did it,
而且我們把他關起來了 可是他仍舊在殺人？
we have him locked up and he's still killing people?
你們這些人一定把這案子搞砸了
You boys sure fucked this one up.
媒體會弄死我們的
The press is gonna kill us.
有人能給我解釋一下嗎？
Can someone explain this to me?
暫時不能
We can't yet.
你怎麼還像安然無事一樣，喬納斯
How did this get away from you, Jonas?
說來複雜，埃普麗爾
It's complicated, April.
他非常狡猾 他非常憤怒
He's very smart. He's very angry.
我們估計有同夥在外面幫助他
We assume he has an accomplice helping him on the outside.
我不要這種談話
I'm not having this conversation.
我不關心他有多聰明 或者是誰在幫他
I don't care how smart he is or who's helping him.
我們將發佈聲明說我們抓到了嫌犯 我們正在追查線索…
We'll release a statement saying we have suspects, we're following leads-
- 無需驚慌 - 市長，我向你保證
- nothing alarming. - Mayor, you have my word,
我們會阻止這傢伙的 他不會再傷害任何人
we are gonna stop this guy. He's not gonna hurt anybody else.
現在開始我給你們每個人加強保安
I'm assigning security to each of you from now on.
控制住局勢，先生們
Get this situation under control, gentlemen.
爸爸？
Dad?
我打賭你不記得我做的那個
I bet you don't remember when I did that.
我打賭我記得
I bet you I do.
怎麼了？
What?
沒什麼
Nothing.
你和你媽媽要度幾天假
You and your mother are going away on a little vacation, that's all.
- 你喜歡假期，對吧？ - 是啊
- You like vacations, right? - Yeah.
好
Good.
可為什麼？
But why?
為什麼不現在去？
Why not now?
好的
Okay.
不需要理由，對吧？
Don't need an excuse, right?
好吧
All right.
別用電話，別用信用卡，別用電腦 只能用現金
No phone calls, no credit cards, no computers- just cash.
爸爸，你來嗎？
Daddy, are you coming?
哦，是的，當然
Oh, yeah, of course.
- 當然我會過去 - 最好這樣，尼克
- Of course I am. - You'd better, Nick.
是你一年級的時候吧？
It was first grade, hmm?
你媽媽幫你拼的
Your mother helped you with the spelling.
是我的生日
It was my birthday.
- 我們得走了！ - 我們走
- Man: We need to go! - Let's go.
- 再見，爸爸 - 再見
- Bye, Daddy. - Bye.
- 我愛你，爸爸 - 我也愛你
- Love you, Daddy. - Love you too.
- 尼克，你的電話線沒有問題 - 很好
- Nick, your phone lines are clear. - Good.
電話線正常，沒被動過手腳 沒什麼問題
No bugs; nothing's been tampered with. You're good.
你本該接受我的條件的
You should have taken my deal.
他媽的六個無辜的人 那就是你要玩的嗎？啊？
That's six fucking innocent people. Is that how you want to play it? Huh?
沒事，沒事 尼克，我知道你很生氣
It's okay. It's okay, Nick. I know you're angry.
那很好，就是要那樣 應該是那樣
That's good. That's what it takes. That's how it has to be.
如果我說你過去是對的 我過去是錯了呢？
What if I said you was right and I was wrong?
如果我說，好吧，我們來審判他們吧？
What if I had said, "Well, let's take them to trial"? Huh?
我會說你進步了
Then I would say you're making progress.
那我們就會敗訴 阿米和多比都會雙雙自由
And we might have lost! And Ames and Darby would both go free.
你還不懂嗎？
Don't you get that?
靠
Fuck.
你不在乎，尼克 你連試都沒試
You didn't care, Nick. You didn't even try.
你本可以昂首闊步走出法庭的
You could have walked out of that courtroom with your head held high.
我本可以接受那點的，尼克
I could have lived with that, Nick.
我會繼續昂首闊步
I keep my head up.
而你將就此終結
And you will end this.
我才剛剛熱身
I'm just getting warmed up.
這就是該死的馮·克勞塞維茨戰爭論
This is Von Clausewitz shit- total fucking war.
你該死
You fuck.
不
No.
我要把這一切推翻
I'm gonna pull the whole thing down.
我要他媽把這瘟疫般、枯爛的廟宇
I'm gonna bring the whole fucking diseased, corrupt temple
扣在你腦袋上
down on your head.
會是驚濤駭浪的
It's gonna be Biblical.
老天，尼克，她是個好孩子
Cantrell: Jesus, Nick, she was a good kid.
是我們把這一切攬上身的嗎？
Did we bring this all on ourselves?
絕對不是
Absolutely not.
你其實也不太確定，是嗎？
You don't actually believe that, do you?
先生們，抱歉 我們得走了
Gentlemen? Sorry, but we need to get going
如果還去參加記者會的話
if we're going to make it to the press conference.
走前我想給你讀一段我以前的演講
I want to read you something from my speech before we go.
我們必須不畏恐懼
"We must not give in to the fear.
我們必須面對那些我們最恐懼的
We must face those things we fear the most.
我們必須懇求我們更好的天使
We must appeaI to our better angels. "
說太多了？
Too much?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
以前你問我是不是我們給自己帶來的這些
It's just before, when you asked if we brought this on ourselves-
其實不是我們
we didn't.
是我自己
I did.
當我年輕的時候，我確實想改變體制
When I was young, I really wanted to change the system.
你知道我準備鬥爭 我準備做最好的不計後果
You know, I was ready to fight. I was gonna be the best no matter what.
你那裡讓一步 你這裡讓一步
You give an inch here, you give an inch there,
你逐漸也進了遊戲
you get caught up in the game.
然後你發現你試圖想改變的體制…
And then you realize that the system that you're trying to change-
卻改變了你
it changed you.
喬納斯，我有些迷失方向了
Jonas, I've lost my way somewhere.
看，記得我告訴過你的
Look, remember what I told you?
最難的部分不是做決定
The hard part isn't making the decision.
而是承受它
It's living with it.
所有人保持警覺
Man: Everybody stay sharp.
我們要上路了
We're on the move.
- 沒事吧？ - 車子掛了
- We all right? - Dunnigan: It's dead.
電子系統掛了
Electrical system's fried.
那邊是怎麼回事？
Man over radio: What's going on back there?
唐尼根，叫他們帶喬納斯離開
Dunnigan, tell them to get Jonas away from here.
那他媽是什麼東西？
What the fuck is that?
趴下，趴下
Get down, get down!
喬納斯！喬納斯！
Jonas! Jonas!
- 喬納斯！喬納斯！ - 不，尼克，蹲下
- Jonas! Jonas! - No, Nick! Get back!
喬納斯，放開你的手
Nick: Jonas! Get your hands off me!
喬納斯，離開車子 喬納斯！
Jonas! Get out of the car! Jonas!
離開車子，放開你的手
Get out of the car! Get off of me!
請聽我說
Dunnigan: Please listen to me!
喬納斯
Jonas!
Jonas.
我叫你處理好這事的
I told you to handle this.
你沒做到
You didn't.
現在我們有個坐牢的瘋子
Now we have a jailed psychopath
計劃讓整座城市臣服於他的腳下
that's managed to bring this entire city to its knees.
我的一個朋友剛剛被殺害
One of my friends was just murdered.
我不止一個朋友走了，市長
More than one of my friends is gone, Mayor.
我該做的事情是炒了你
What I should do is fire you.
嗯？現在
Hmm? Right now.
我辭職
I resign.
- 那是你真正的回答麼 - 我想那樣最好
- Is that your real answer? - I think that's best.
不行
No.
我不允許你辭職 把聖經拿給我
I'm not gonna allow that to happen. Bring me the Bible.
我不會讓罪犯決定費城該不該有地方檢察官
I'm not gonna let some criminal decide whether Philadelphia has a DA or not.
現在，你是代理地方檢察官
As of now, you're acting District Attorney.
我們稍後會有個正式的宣誓
We'll have a formal swearing in later.
目前這就足夠了 起立！
For now this will suffice. Stand up.
把你的左手放在聖經上 舉起你的右手
Put your left hand on the Bible. Raise your right hand.
跟我復讀
Repeat after me.
- 我，尼古拉斯·瑞斯 - 我，尼古拉斯·瑞斯
- I, Nicolas Rice... - I, Nicolas Rice...
- 莊嚴地發誓… - 莊嚴地發誓…
- ... do solemnly swear... - ... do solemnly swear...
- 我將支持… - 我將支持…
- ... that I will support... - ... that I will support...
- 服從… - 服從…
- ... obey... - ... obey...
並捍衛美利堅聯邦憲法…
...and defend the Constitution of the United States...
以及賓夕法尼亞州法律…
...and the Constitution of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania...
民眾不上班，小孩不上學
People aren't going to work; kids aren't going to schooI.
他們很害怕 我不能怪他們
They're scared, and I don't blame them.
所以我要動用費城法典的緊急條款
So I'm implementing the emergency provision of the Philadelphia code.
我們將本市戒嚴
We're gonna lock this city down.
現在開始，誰都不能在本市自由行動
Starting now, no one moves in this city unrestricted.
我要展示勇氣給大家看
I want a show of force for the public-
制服警員，警探 12小時輪班
uniforms, detectives, 12-hour shifts.
每個角落安置武裝警察
Put an armed cop on every corner.
如果有必要給停車收費員霰彈槍 那就給
If you have to give shotguns to the meter maids, do it.
民眾就不會懷疑
There should be no doubt in people's minds
這個城市是安全的 在我們的掌握之中
that this city is secure and under our control.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，克萊德 我明白了
Okay, Clyde. I get it.
聽著，殺死坎特雷爾的裝置
Dunnigan: Listen, that contraption that killed Cantrell,
是一種武裝後的拆彈機器人
it was a weaponized bomb-disposal robot.
你能相信麼？
Can you believe that?
那該死的東西有影像，夜視鏡… 說出來的都有
Damn thing had video, night vision- you name it.
就像軍事應用接口，我的老天
It's like military APl, for Christ's sakes.
那是反坦克的，尼克
That's anti-tank rounds, Nick.
我想他會把你留作壓軸
I think he's saving you for last.
尼克，我是認真的
Nick, I'm serious.
我感激你的洞察力
I appreciate the insight.
尼克，你得趕在他前面 如果你想活命
Nick, you gotta get in front of this guy if you want to stay alive.
我可能有辦法了…
I may have a way-
一個朋友的東西會幫我解決
something a friend is helping me out with.
你朋友是誰？
Who's your friend?
一個叫切斯特的朋友 我會給你回電話
A friend named Chester. I'll call you back.
謝謝，莎拉
Thank you, Sarah.
我是尼克，給我最近10年這裡賣掉的
This is Nick. Give me the real-estate listing
每一筆工業地產的清單
of every industrial property sold here in the last 10 years.
混蛋東西
Motherfucker.
你在開玩笑，是吧？
You're kidding me, right?
你是說這個地方是克萊德的
You're saying Clyde owns this place?
事情很明顯，對吧？
Something about it sticks out, right?
嗯
Yeah.
我認為你要做一件事，是我想的那樣嗎？
What- are you gonna do what I think you're gonna do?
- 他的公民權怎麼辦？ - 去他媽的公民權
- What about his civil rights? - Fuck his civiI rights.
哈哈，不錯
Yes!
這裡面一定有問題
There's got to be something in here.
嗯
Dunnigan: Yeah.
記得這個在屋子外嗎？
Remember this from outside the house?
恩
Yeah.
打開那個
Get that right there.
真他媽難以置信
Dunnigan: Un-fucking-believable.
看吧
Look at this.
當心腳下
Nick: Watch your step.
這傢伙挖隧道到監獄？
This guy tunneled into prison?
哦，該死
Nick: Oh, shit.
靠…橡膠炸彈
Dunnigan: Fuck- Semtex.
警察制服，其它的偽裝品
Got police uniforms, other disguises.
他挖通了每個牢房
Nick: He tunneled into every cell.
這邊
Over here.
他故意要轉到禁閉室
He wanted to be transferred to solitary.
給你個驚喜，王八蛋
Surprise, motherfucker.
- 他不在這裡 - 如果他不在那，那會在哪？
- He's not here! - If he's not there, then where is he?
諾莫斯，你眼睛怎麼了？
Nomos, what happened to your eye?
哦，說來話長
Oh, long story.
站住，先生
Stop right there, sir.
請你讓我看看證件
Let me see your ID, please.
- 好的，當然 - 謝謝
- Yeah, sure. - Thank you.
轉身，先生 手臂伸開
Turn around, sir. Extend your arms.
今晚有活動嗎？
Something going on tonight?
- 市長 - 嗯，市長
- The mayor. - Mmm, mayor.
看看這個
Look at this.
他偷偷接通了監獄攝像機
He tapped into the prison cameras.
老天，到處都是攝像機
Jesus, he's got cameras everywhere.
- 該死 - 那是你家嗎？
- Shit. - Is that your house?
是的
Yes.
寶貝，告訴我你們沒事
Baby, please tell me you're okay.
丹尼斯，她在哪？
Denise- where is she?
她跟你在一起？ 你確定？
Is she with you? Are you sure?
好
Okay.
待著別動 我一會再解釋
Stay where you are. I'll explain later.
我愛你
I love you.
（取得勝利就要重兵集結在 所有權力活動中心--敵人的重心）
馮·克勞塞維茨
Nick: Von Clausewitz.
看看那個
Look at that.
他在市政廳
He's at City Hall.
你可以走了，先生
You're free to go, sir.
- 抱歉造成不便，先生 - 不用，沒關係
- Sorry for the inconvenience, sir. - No, don't worry about it.
安全要比抱歉重要，是吧？
Better to be safe than sorry, right?
準備疏散大樓
Dunnigan: Get ready to evacuate the building.
我們需要一支戰術小隊和防爆小組
We'll need a tactical unit and a bomb squad.
壞主意，叫他們悄悄進去
Bad idea. Have them come in soft.
如果謝爾頓認出我或我們中任何一個人 事情就糟糕了
If Shelton spots them or any of us, we're fucked.
嘿
Hey.
- 戰術小隊在哪？ - 正趕來
- Where's the tactical team? - En route.
- 他們悄悄地過來，不鳴警笛 - 拆彈部隊呢？
- They're coming in soft- no sirens. - Bomb squad?
你正在看著呢
You're looking at it.
對，那我們走北邊樓梯 你走西邊
Right, okay. We take the north surge; you take the west.
我們再聯繫
We'll call.
- 喔，喔，喔 - 請出示證件
- Whoa whoa whoa whoa. - IDs, please.
- 他是地區檢察官 - 很不錯，麻煩出示證件
- He's the fucking DA. - Good for him. IDs, please.
今晚這裡怎麼回事
What's going on here tonight?
- 所有高層在這開安保會議 - 哪一層？
- Security meeting with all the brass. - What floor?
六樓…會議室
6th floor- caucus room.
- 這是幾樓？ - 那是五樓，先生
- What floor is this? - That's the 5th floor, sir.
正好是高層會議室的下面
Directly below the caucus room.
如果我們發現混蛋正在作案 我們要抓活的
You catch this motherfucker red-handed, we gotta take him alive.
他在哪？
Where is he?
我們到底在找什麼？
What the fuck are we looking for?
等等，等等
Wait wait wait.
在那
Right there.
退後，別碰任何東西
Garza: Stand back. Don't touch anything.
那絕對不是我的第一感覺
It wasn't exactly my first instinct.
麻煩給我看看證件
Can I see your ID, please?
好了，下一輛，往前走
All right, next car, pull forward!
爆炸物
Garza: Malglinite.
那是凝固汽油彈 這鬼東西基本上會炸跨整層樓
That's napalm, basically. This shit'll take out the entire floor
和這層上方的樓層
and the one above us.
看起來…好像是由這支手機所觸發
Looks like it's- looks like it's triggered by this cell phone here.
什麼？一來電話就激活了？
What? So an incoming call arms it?
是的，也許30秒就爆炸了
Yeah. Maybe 30 seconds till boom time.
- 天呀 - 唐尼根，你在幹嘛
- Jesus. - Dunnigan, what are you doing?
- 我要打給市長的保安人員 - 不行
- I'm calling the mayor's security. - We can't.
克萊德在盯著 如果他看見他們疏散，他會引爆的
Clyde is watching. He sees him evacuate and he will detonate this thing.
我們不能向市長透露
We don't tell the mayor anything.
那我們該怎麼做？
So what do we do?
等一下
Man: Wait a second.
來了
We've got something.
他要停下了
Man over radio: He's pulling up.
市長埃普麗爾·亨利
Man: Mayor April Henry.
感謝各位的匆忙趕來
Thank you for coming in on short notice.
我有一個簡單的問題
Mayor: I have one simple question.
為什麼克萊德·謝爾頓還在我的城市？
Why is Clyde Shelton still in my city?
我現在拒絕相信
Now I refuse to believe
這個人比國土安全部
that one man is smarter than Homeland Security,
FBI，行政司法長官或費城警察還聰明
the FBl, the sheriff's department, or Philly PD.
我不管我們怎麼做
I don't care how we do it, or what kind
或者必須啟動哪種的晦澀的司法程序
of obscure legaI justification we have to invoke, gentlemen.
先生們，我不在乎我們要遵守哪條法律
I don't care what laws we have to bend.
但我相信國土安全法案會有一個條款
I am sure that there is a provision of the Homeland Security Act
是我們可以啟動的
that we can activate.
明天之前將他趕出這裡
Just get him out of here by tomorrow.
克萊德？
Nick: Clyde?
尼克
Nick.
我沒料到還會有人陪我
I wasn't expecting company.
嗯，早知道就先稍微打掃一下
Yeah, I would have- I would have cleaned up a little.
從未見過任何人挖隧道到監獄
Never seen anybody tunnel into prison before.
被關進禁閉室的法子很聰明
And the solitary confinement? That was clever.
嗯，那正是贏家的玩法
Well, that's how winners play.
我們要讓其他人信服 他做的每一步都是正確的
We convince the other guy he's making all the right moves.
那你抓住我同夥了嗎？
So did you ever catch my accomplice?
是的，當然
Yeah, I did.
現在是你的末路了
It's the end of the road for you now.
你玩弄了我們，克萊德 你真的耍得我們團團轉
You played us, Clyde. You played us real good.
謝謝
Thank you.
知道麼，很高興你終於能夠賞識
You know, I'm glad you finally get to appreciate
我所做的這一切努力了
some of the effort that I put into all of this.
你特別想強調某點，克萊德
Well, you set out to make a point, Clyde.
你做到了
You made it.
不，人們仍然不懂
No, people still don't get it.
他們不重視我試圖說的 尼克，不過很快地他們就會了
They don't appreciate what I'm trying to say, Nick, but they will soon enough.
我關心過的一個人曾告訴過我
A man I cared about once told me
我們不能撤回我們已做了的決定
that we can't retract the decisions that we've made,
我們只能影響今後我們要做的決定
we can only affect the decisions we're going to make from here.
- 現在你想拯救我嗎，尼克？ - 我在給你一條出路
- Are you trying to save me now, Nick? - I'm giving you a way out.
差別很大
Big difference.
站在你一直在宣揚的那些立場上
Stand up for those principles you've been preaching.
所以你看我們都要負責 克萊德，包括你在內
See, we're all held accountable, Clyde. That includes you.
為何不做正確的事呢？
Why don't we do the right thing here?
我是在做正確的事，尼克
I'm doing the right thing, Nick.
你只需以那種方式去看
You just have to see it that way.
靠著謀殺那些人
By murdering all those people,
你的所作所為只會摧毀你對女兒的記憶
all you're doing is destroying the memory of your daughter
也會對很多人造成你正遭受的痛苦
and causing the same pain that you're suffering from.
那麼你有何建議呢，尼克？ 再做另一次交易嗎？
So what do you suggest, Nick? Make another deaI?
提最後一次條件？ 是那樣子嗎？
One finaI offer? Is that what it is?
我不再與殺人兇手做交易了，克萊德
I don't make deals with murderers anymore, Clyde.
你教我的
You taught me that.
終於
Finally.
幹得好，好極了
Well done. Bravo.
也許我並非是個很糟的老師
Maybe I wasn't such a bad teacher after all.
如果你幹這事，克萊德 這個決定
If you go through with this, Clyde, it's a decision
你後半輩子都要承受這個決定
you'll have to live with for the rest of your life.
對不起，尼克
I'm sorry, Nick.
我也是
Me too.
如我說過的，克萊德
Like I said, Clyde,
你後半輩子都要承受這個決定
it's a decision you'll have to live with for the rest of your life,
我想現在大概還剩25秒鐘吧？
which I figure by now is about 25 more seconds.
謝謝觀賞
「未曾見一夜」
# Ain't seen a night #
「雲開月明」
# Things work out right #
「消逝」
# Go by #
「心中成大事」
# Things on my mind #
「然時不我待」
# And I just don't have the time #
「似物是人非」
# And it don't seem right #
「未見有時」
# Ain't seen a day #
「斯人已無言」
# That I don't hear people say #
「自知人之將去」
# They know they're gonna die #
《守法公民》 「此事已成瘋癲」
# This may seem a little bit crazy #
「然斯人亦當勤勉」
# But I don't think you should be so lazy #
「似曾相識處」
# If you think you've heard this before #
「飲酒至闌珊」
# Well, stick around #
「盡其詳」
# I'm gonna tell you more #
「吾等皆草民」
# One just like the other #
「惡善伴行生」
# Sin's a good man's brother #
「知否？」
# But is that right? #
「汝知此不可為」
# You tell me that I don't #
「吾遂不為」
# Then I say I won't #
「然尚可為」
# But then I might #
「此行或可眾人期」
# You said this is the way it's supposed to be #
「卻吾念甚篤」
# But it just don't seem right to me #
「且視而不見」
# And that's outta sight #
「民教重於天」
# Some folks need an education #
「棄之國將不國」
# Don't give up or we'll lose the nation #
「天下之變」
# You say we need a revolution? #
「仿若」
# It seems to be #
「唯此一解矣」
# The only solution. #